<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Samir Lamara</title>
    <link>https://slamara.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Samir Lamara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 16:40:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://slamara.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal activity monitoring</title>
      <link>https://slamara.github.io/project/activitymonitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 16:40:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slamara.github.io/project/activitymonitoring/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis project makes use of data from a personal activity monitoring device which counts the number of steps taken by an anonymous individual in 5 minutes intervals throughout the day. The dataset was collected within a period of two months (October and November 2012).
The variables included in this dataset are:
steps: Number of steps taking in a 5-minute interval (missing values are coded as NA)
date: The date on which the measurement was taken in YYYY-MM-DD format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of fine particulate matter pollution in the US</title>
      <link>https://slamara.github.io/project/airquality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 16:24:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slamara.github.io/project/airquality/</guid>
      <description>Among the numerous air pollutants, the fine particulate matter (PM2.5) is one of the most harmful to human health. In the US, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) is in charge of setting the ambient air quality standards, tracking the emissions of the pollutants into the atmosphere, and releasing a database on emissions approximatly every 3 years. This database is known as the National Emissions Inventory (NEI). For more details, see the EPA National Emissions Inventory web site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual household electric power consumption</title>
      <link>https://slamara.github.io/project/electricpconsumption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 16:08:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slamara.github.io/project/electricpconsumption/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this project is to examine how household energy usage varies over a 2-day period in February, 2007 using the base plotting system. The data used in here (in particular, the “Individual household electric power consumption Data Set”) are from the UC Irvine Machine Learning Repository, a popular repository for machine learning datasets.
library(sqldf)library(dplyr)library(ggplot2)# Estimate the memory usagepaste0(&amp;quot;As the dataset has 2880 rows and 9 columns, it requires about &amp;quot;, round(2880 * 9 * 8 / 2^20, 2), &amp;quot; Megabytes in memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting and cleaning data</title>
      <link>https://slamara.github.io/project/gcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 18:05:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slamara.github.io/project/gcd/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe purpose of this project is to show the ability to collect, work with, and clean a data set. The goal is to prepare tidy data that can be used for later analysis.
The data used in this project represent data collected from the accelerometers of Samsung Galaxy S smartphones. For a full description please visit the following website:
http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Human+Activity+Recognition+Using+Smartphones 1
Here are the data for the project:
https://d396qusza40orc.cloudfront.net/getdata%2Fprojectfiles%2FUCI%20HAR%20Dataset.zip</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ranking US Hospitals</title>
      <link>https://slamara.github.io/project/rankingushospitals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 18:05:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slamara.github.io/project/rankingushospitals/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThe purpose of this project is to rank over 4000 US hospitals according to the quality of care. The data represent a small subset of the data available at the Hospital Compare web site (http://hospitalcompare.hhs.gov) run by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.
The zip file for this project contains three files:
outcome-of-care-measures.csv: Contains information about 30-day mortality and readmission rates for heart attacks, heart failure, and pneumonia for over 4,000 hospitals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>